ABOUT ME

After a 3.5 years period in industrial sector: firstly as a project engineer and then in controlling department, I have decided to switch my career into Data Analysis.

After a successful self-training period in analytics I've joined Stuart a last-mile delivery scale up in Business Operations and then as Product Analyst in Network Optimisation

LINKS

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-assenza395141/

Data Self Training Portfolio: https://kassenzag8.github.io/

LANGUAGES

FRENCH - NATIVE

ITIAI IAN - NATIVE

ENGLISH - PROFESSIONAL WORKING PROFICIENCY

KEVIN ASSENZA

O Pa

Paris, France



0770335537

 \sim

kevin.assenza@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

STUART

Paris Feb 2024 - Present

Product Analyst

- Collaborated cross-functionally with Engineering, Product Management, and Design teams to develop a reactive tool aimed at enhancing platform reliability through strategic incentives and improved courier communications for 3 European markets
- Executed Hypothesis Testing methodologies to extract actionable insights, informing and steering product development decisions.
- Designed and implemented SQL pipelines alongside Tableau dashboards for comprehensive monitoring of critical product performance indicators.

STUART

Paris Aug 2022 - Feb 2024

Business Analyst

- Engineered an automated Python solution for managing high-priority requests, including GDPR and <u>Government Ind</u> <u>icators</u>, streamlining the Courier Digital Onboarding process and saving 20 hours per week in Operations.
- Crafted and deployed a Python-based earnings <u>compensat</u> <u>ion model</u> for the French market
- Collaborated with Operations to refine incentive strategies
 ~ 60k€ weekly, increasing profitability through data-driven
 optimizations.
- Provided pivotal support to the Data Science team in the development and deployment of Machine Learning products into production environments.

CLAAS

Harsewinkel -Germany Aug 2021 - Apr 2022

International Graduate Program - Finance/Controlling

- Completed an intensive 4-month training in controlling concepts acquiring foundational finance skills
- Advanced to a 6-month tenure at the Group's HQ in Germany: developed an automated Working Capital Dashboard and provided robust support in daily controlling processes

CLAAS

Le Mans Sep 2018 - Aug 2021

Industrial Project Engineer in Apprenticeship

- Developed and managed a reworking workshop for internal scraps with part-time therapeutical employees - reduce scrapping cost by 50% ~ 250k€.
- Developed two sub-assembly lines to reach new industrial concepts in order to increase production efficiency, quality and operator ergonomy ~200k€.

EDUCATION

SELF TRAINING

Paris 2022

Data Analyst

<u>Portfolio</u> - Self Training in Analytics Skills : Python, SQL, Tableau, Statistics

ARTS ET MÉTIERS

Angers 2021

Master of Science - Industrial Engineering

Diploma equivalent Master of Science in Industrial Engineering - Ranking: 30/1200

LYCÉE CHAPTAL

Paris 2018

Preparatory Classes

Intensive post-Baccalaureat studies to prepare for competitive entrance exams to graduate engineering schools